<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>security on &gt; /dev/null 2&gt;&amp;1</title>
    <link>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/tags/security/</link>
    <description>Recent content in security on &gt; /dev/null 2&gt;&amp;1</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Aug 2021 15:56:52 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.heimsbakk.net/tags/security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Wireguard VPN server</title>
      <link>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20210808-wireguard/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Aug 2021 15:56:52 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20210808-wireguard/</guid>
      <description>From Wikipedia: WireGuard is a communication protocol and free and open-source software that implements encrypted virtual private networks (VPNs), and was designed with the goals of ease of use, high speed performance, and low attack surface.
Installation Install the package that contain the wg-quick helper tool.
Fedora sudo dnf install -y wireguard-tools  Ubuntu sudo apt-get install -y wireguard-tools resolvconf  Configuration Wireguard is a point to point VPN.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Malware lists for PiHole</title>
      <link>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20210227-pihole-lists/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2021 18:30:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20210227-pihole-lists/</guid>
      <description>Excerpt from Wikipedia: Pi-hole is a Linux network-level advertisement and Internet tracker blocking application which acts as a DNS sinkhole and optionally a DHCP server, intended for use on a private network. It is designed for use on embedded devices with network capability, such as the Raspberry Pi, but it can be used on other machines running Linux, including cloud implementations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>List CPU vulnerabilities</title>
      <link>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20200731-vulnerabilities/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2020 16:25:02 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20200731-vulnerabilities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Oneliner to list your CPU vulnerabilities and mitigations. Read more about the different vulnerabilities and mitigations at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kernel.org/doc/html/latest/admin-guide/hw-vuln/index.html&#34;&gt;Hardware vulnerabilities&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design an online ransomware safe backup with restic</title>
      <link>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20190911-restic/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20190911-restic/</guid>
      <description>The only way to be safe for ransomware, except for keeping a offline backup, is to have a immutable online backup.
restic is a deduplication backup sofware, designed for ease of use and security. Rclone is a versatile program for syncing data between a huge variety of protocols and cloud providers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SSH with YubiKey NEO on Fedora made easy</title>
      <link>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20180105-yubikey/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20180105-yubikey/</guid>
      <description>Your private SSH key is the key for the kingdom. This means always having a password on the key. With YubiKey, you can keep your secret key outside your machine too.
Excerpt from Wikipedia: The YubiKey allows users to sign, encrypt and decrypt messages without exposing the private keys to the outside world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Only Firefox is safe post Heartblead</title>
      <link>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20140512-revocation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20140512-revocation/</guid>
      <description>oSteve Gibson have a nice round-up where he explains how certificate revocation does work and why Chrome and Chromiums certificate revocation scheme doesn&amp;rsquo;t work. I recommend to read both Steve Gibson&amp;rsquo;s article on An Evaluation of the Effectiveness of Chrome&amp;rsquo;s CRLSets and Adam Langley&amp;rsquo;s in my opinion a bit missplaced answer Revocation still doesn&amp;rsquo;t work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OCSP Stapling on Apache</title>
      <link>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20140504-ocsp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20140504-ocsp/</guid>
      <description>Excerpt from Remy van Elsts tutorial: OCSP stapling is an enhancement to the standard OCSP protocol that delivers OCSP responses from the server with the certificate, eliminating the need for relying parties (web users) to check OCSP responses with the issuing CA. This has the effect of reducing bandwidth, improving perceived site performance, and increasing security for everyone involved in establishing the secure session.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to get A&#43; on SSL Labs</title>
      <link>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20140503-ssl/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20140503-ssl/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This will show how to get A+ on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ssllabs.com/ssltest&#34;&gt;SSL Server Test&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ssllabs.com&#34;&gt;Qualys SSL Labs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring OpenVPN server on RTN66U</title>
      <link>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20140501-easyrsa/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20140501-easyrsa/</guid>
      <description>The router firmware Tomato, see previous post RT-N66u with Tomato by Shibby firmware, can act as an OpenVPN server.
Using open Wi-Fi access points can be very useful and necessary, but it is inherently insecure. Using the router as an OpenVPN server can increase your privacy and security when you are on the go.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Better entropy with haveged</title>
      <link>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20140429-haveged/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20140429-haveged/</guid>
      <description>Entropy is important for generating good encryption keys. Do you have a busy server relying on crypto, generating keys, you need lot of good entropy. Or if you have a disk less system you don&amp;rsquo;t get as much entropy from the kernel that you may wish. One way to get a lot of good entropy is to use haveged.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
