<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>vagrant on &gt; /dev/null 2&gt;&amp;1</title>
    <link>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/tags/vagrant/</link>
    <description>Recent content in vagrant on &gt; /dev/null 2&gt;&amp;1</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 15:43:42 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.heimsbakk.net/tags/vagrant/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Libvirt and Vagrant</title>
      <link>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20200728-vagrant-libvirt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 15:43:42 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20200728-vagrant-libvirt/</guid>
      <description>Libvirt is the default toolkit to manage virtualization platforms on Linux. Libvirt and qemu is a great combination with Vagrant. It&amp;rsquo;s the default combination on most Linux systems, also on my favorite - Fedora.
This combination allows for some awesome features and some restrictions. One of the restrictions is that Ubuntu isn&amp;rsquo;t available as a box, but Debian is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vagrant with Ubuntu Focal (20.04)</title>
      <link>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20200728-vagrant-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 11:49:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20200728-vagrant-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>Vagrant is a great way to script development environments for system administrators. It works with full virtualization and is closer to the real hardware than container systems.
There is a bug in the latest version of Ubuntu (Vagrant Box) that makes it hang during boot. It even hangs the VirtualBox and makes the GUI misbehave.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vagrant with OpenStack</title>
      <link>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20141218-vagrant-openstack/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20141218-vagrant-openstack/</guid>
      <description>If you want to use Vagrant with OpenStack, you need to prepare Vagrant with installing the vagrant-openstack-plugin. I had some problems installing it directly through vagrant plugin install. I had to clone it from Github and install it manually.
One time configuration Install OpenStack plugin in Vagrant cd /tmp git clone https://github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vagrant, development environments made easy</title>
      <link>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20140525-vagrant/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20140525-vagrant/</guid>
      <description>Prototyping and testing configurations and system installations is time consuming on traditional hardware. That is why I started using Vagrant for nearly all development, prototyping and testing. It&amp;rsquo;s free and really easy to use. If you install VirtualBox sudo apt-get install virtualbox first, you&amp;rsquo;ll be up and running in no time.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
