<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>uris on &gt; /dev/null 2&gt;&amp;1</title>
    <link>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/categories/uris/</link>
    <description>Recent content in uris on &gt; /dev/null 2&gt;&amp;1</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 00:28:09 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.heimsbakk.net/categories/uris/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Barcode Content</title>
      <link>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20200811-barcode/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 00:28:09 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20200811-barcode/</guid>
      <description>This is a copy from the ZXing repo wiki pages at commit hash 3110236. ZXing is an open-source, multi-format 1D/2D barcode image processing library implemented in Java, with ports to other languages.
 Much has been said about 2D barcodes, and the discussion has focused on the format of the 2D barcode itself &amp;ndash; QR Code, Data Matrix, and so on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn Docker with LearnDocker.online</title>
      <link>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20200811-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 00:08:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20200811-docker/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve seen a lot of learning resources for Docker. Personally I think this is one of the better resources for beginners. Enjoy!
Excerpt from the website: LearnDocker.online is the most comprehensive online Docker training program on the planet.
 LearnDocker.online  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Portable Hardware Locality (hwloc)</title>
      <link>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20200801-hwloc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 16:58:55 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20200801-hwloc/</guid>
      <description>From the website: The Portable Hardware Locality (hwloc) software package provides a portable abstraction (across OS, versions, architectures, &amp;hellip;) of the hierarchical topology of modern architectures, including NUMA memory nodes, sockets, shared caches, cores and simultaneous multithreading. It also gathers various system attributes such as cache and memory information as well as the locality of I/O devices such as network interfaces, InfiniBand HCAs or GPUs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distributed syncing with Syncthing</title>
      <link>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20160326-syncthing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20160326-syncthing/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to ditch Dropbox for a long time. But the need for synchronizing folders between my computers have held me back. Syncthing solves this for me. It&amp;rsquo;s decentralized syncrhonization between all my units, including my phone, without the need to go through a 3rd party server.
Excerpt from Syncthings homepage: Syncthing replaces proprietary sync and cloud services with something open, trustworthy and decentralized.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compressed RAM based block devices</title>
      <link>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20150111-zram/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20150111-zram/</guid>
      <description>From zram documentation: The zram module creates RAM based block devices named /dev/zram(= 0, 1, &amp;hellip;). Pages written to these disks are compressed and stored in memory itself. These disks allow very fast I/O and compression provides good amounts of memory savings. Some of the usecases include /tmp storage, use as swap disks, various caches under /var and maybe many more :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vagrant, development environments made easy</title>
      <link>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20140525-vagrant/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20140525-vagrant/</guid>
      <description>Prototyping and testing configurations and system installations is time consuming on traditional hardware. That is why I started using Vagrant for nearly all development, prototyping and testing. It&amp;rsquo;s free and really easy to use. If you install VirtualBox sudo apt-get install virtualbox first, you&amp;rsquo;ll be up and running in no time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Only Firefox is safe post Heartblead</title>
      <link>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20140512-revocation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20140512-revocation/</guid>
      <description>oSteve Gibson have a nice round-up where he explains how certificate revocation does work and why Chrome and Chromiums certificate revocation scheme doesn&amp;rsquo;t work. I recommend to read both Steve Gibson&amp;lsquo;s article on An Evaluation of the Effectiveness of Chrome&amp;rsquo;s CRLSets and Adam Langley&amp;rsquo;s in my opinion a bit missplaced answer Revocation still doesn&amp;rsquo;t work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OCSP Stapling on Apache</title>
      <link>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20140504-ocsp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20140504-ocsp/</guid>
      <description>Excerpt from Remy van Elsts tutorial: OCSP stapling is an enhancement to the standard OCSP protocol that delivers OCSP responses from the server with the certificate, eliminating the need for relying parties (web users) to check OCSP responses with the issuing CA. This has the effect of reducing bandwidth, improving perceived site performance, and increasing security for everyone involved in establishing the secure session.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Better entropy with haveged</title>
      <link>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20140429-haveged/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20140429-haveged/</guid>
      <description>Entropy is important for generating good encryption keys. Do you have a busy server relying on crypto, generating keys, you need lot of good entropy. Or if you have a disk less system you don&amp;rsquo;t get as much entropy from the kernel that you may wish. One way to get a lot of good entropy is to use haveged.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud virtual machine</title>
      <link>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20140413-digitalocea/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20140413-digitalocea/</guid>
      <description>Easiest way I know to create cloud virtual machine is to create a Droplet on Digital Ocean.
 DigialOcean  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SSL Server Test</title>
      <link>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20140413-ssllabs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20140413-ssllabs/</guid>
      <description>Run Qualys SSL Labs test to test the strength and combability of SSL certificate.
 SSL Server Test  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scaling in the Linux Networking Stack</title>
      <link>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20140412-link/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20140412-link/</guid>
      <description>Documentation for increaseing parallelism and performance for multi-processor systems.
 scaling.html  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>