<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on &gt; /dev/null 2&gt;&amp;1</title>
    <link>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on &gt; /dev/null 2&gt;&amp;1</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 15:43:59 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Chess resources</title>
      <link>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20200817-chess/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 15:43:59 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20200817-chess/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From Wikipedia: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chess&#34;&gt;Chess&lt;/a&gt; is a two-player strategy board game played on a checkered board with 64 squares arranged in an 8×8 square grid.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Origami / Paper Folding</title>
      <link>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20200817-origami/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 14:36:38 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20200817-origami/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From Wikipedia: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Origami&#34;&gt;Origami&lt;/a&gt; (折り紙, Japanese pronunciation: [oɾiɡami] or [oɾiꜜɡami], from ori meaning &amp;ldquo;folding&amp;rdquo;, and kami meaning &amp;ldquo;paper&amp;rdquo; (kami changes to gami due to rendaku)) is the art of paper folding, which is often associated with Japanese culture. In modern usage, the word &amp;ldquo;origami&amp;rdquo; is used as an inclusive term for all folding practices, regardless of their culture of origin.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tear free desktop on Intel graphics</title>
      <link>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20200811-tearfree/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 22:48:52 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20200811-tearfree/</guid>
      <description>Excerpt from man intel, option &amp;ldquo;TearFree&amp;rdquo;: Disable or enable TearFree updates. This option forces X to perform all rendering to a backbuffer prior to updating the actual display. It requires an extra memory allocation the same size as a framebuffer, the occasional extra copy, and requires Damage tracking. Thus enabling TearFree requires more memory and is slower (reduced throughput) and introduces a small amount of output latency, but it should not impact input latency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Barcode Content</title>
      <link>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20200811-barcode/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 00:28:09 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20200811-barcode/</guid>
      <description>This is a copy from the ZXing repo wiki pages at commit hash 3110236. ZXing is an open-source, multi-format 1D/2D barcode image processing library implemented in Java, with ports to other languages.
 Much has been said about 2D barcodes, and the discussion has focused on the format of the 2D barcode itself &amp;ndash; QR Code, Data Matrix, and so on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn Docker with LearnDocker.online</title>
      <link>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20200811-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 00:08:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20200811-docker/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve seen a lot of learning resources for Docker. Personally I think this is one of the better resources for beginners. Enjoy!
Excerpt from the website: LearnDocker.online is the most comprehensive online Docker training program on the planet.
 LearnDocker.online  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>bmon - bandwidth monitor and rate estimator</title>
      <link>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20200807-bmon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 23:47:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20200807-bmon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tgraf/bmon&#34;&gt;bmon&lt;/a&gt; is a monitoring and debugging tool to capture networking related statistics and prepare them visually in a human friendly way.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ncdu - NCurses Disk Usage</title>
      <link>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20200807-ncdu/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 23:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20200807-ncdu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.yorhel.nl/ncdu&#34;&gt;ncdu&lt;/a&gt; (NCurses Disk Usage) is a curses-based version of the well-known &lt;code&gt;du&lt;/code&gt;, and provides a fast way to see what directories are using your disk space.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>tldr - a supplement to man</title>
      <link>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20200807-tldr/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 14:22:43 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20200807-tldr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Excerpt from &lt;a href=&#34;https://tldr.sh/&#34;&gt;tldr.sh&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;em&gt;The tldr pages are a community effort to simplify the beloved man pages with practical examples.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get more information at &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tldr-pages/tldr&#34;&gt;tldr-pages at GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>e1000e: Detected Hardware Unit Hang</title>
      <link>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20200807-hardware-unit-hang/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 01:20:05 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20200807-hardware-unit-hang/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are you, as I, suffering from &lt;em&gt;Detected Hardware Unit Hang&lt;/em&gt; in the kernel log from an e1000e network card? How do you notice it. A transfer goes to zero bytes for around 10 seconds, then restarts, then goes to zero, then restarts and so on&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Portable Hardware Locality (hwloc)</title>
      <link>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20200801-hwloc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 16:58:55 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20200801-hwloc/</guid>
      <description>From the website: The Portable Hardware Locality (hwloc) software package provides a portable abstraction (across OS, versions, architectures, &amp;hellip;) of the hierarchical topology of modern architectures, including NUMA memory nodes, sockets, shared caches, cores and simultaneous multithreading. It also gathers various system attributes such as cache and memory information as well as the locality of I/O devices such as network interfaces, InfiniBand HCAs or GPUs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>List CPU vulnerabilities</title>
      <link>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20200731-vulnerabilities/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2020 16:25:02 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20200731-vulnerabilities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Oneliner to list your CPU vulnerabilities and mitigations. Read more about the different vulnerabilities and mitigations at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kernel.org/doc/html/latest/admin-guide/hw-vuln/index.html&#34;&gt;Hardware vulnerabilities&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bootstrap Debian VM with virt-install</title>
      <link>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20200730-libvirt-bootstrap/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 18:57:10 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20200730-libvirt-bootstrap/</guid>
      <description>Installing a small Debian VM from scratch with only one partition. Makes later resizing easier. This was done on Fedora 32.
Preparations Install software libvirt is already installed on Fedora 32. It&amp;rsquo;s used in Gnome Boxes. We will not use that for this. We&amp;rsquo;ll do it the old fashioned way with virt-install.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Libvirt and Vagrant</title>
      <link>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20200728-vagrant-libvirt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 15:43:42 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20200728-vagrant-libvirt/</guid>
      <description>Libvirt is the default toolkit to manage virtualization platforms on Linux. Libvirt and qemu is a great combination with Vagrant. It&amp;rsquo;s the default combination on most Linux systems, also on my favorite - Fedora.
This combination allows for some awesome features and some restrictions. One of the restrictions is that Ubuntu isn&amp;rsquo;t available as a box, but Debian is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vagrant with Ubuntu Focal (20.04)</title>
      <link>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20200728-vagrant-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 11:49:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20200728-vagrant-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>Vagrant is a great way to script development environments for system administrators. It works with full virtualization and is closer to the real hardware than container systems.
There is a bug in the latest version of Ubuntu (Vagrant Box) that makes it hang during boot. It even hangs the VirtualBox and makes the GUI misbehave.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design an online ransomware safe backup with restic</title>
      <link>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20190911-restic/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20190911-restic/</guid>
      <description>The only way to be safe for ransomware, except for keeping a offline backup, is to have a immutable online backup.
restic is a deduplication backup sofware, designed for ease of use and security. Rclone is a versatile program for syncing data between a huge variety of protocols and cloud providers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SSH with YubiKey NEO on Fedora made easy</title>
      <link>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20180105-yubikey/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20180105-yubikey/</guid>
      <description>Your private SSH key is the key for the kingdom. This means always having a password on the key. With YubiKey, you can keep your secret key outside your machine too.
Excerpt from Wikipedia: The YubiKey allows users to sign, encrypt and decrypt messages without exposing the private keys to the outside world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distributed syncing with Syncthing</title>
      <link>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20160326-syncthing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20160326-syncthing/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to ditch Dropbox for a long time. But the need for synchronizing folders between my computers have held me back. Syncthing solves this for me. It&amp;rsquo;s decentralized syncrhonization between all my units, including my phone, without the need to go through a 3rd party server.
Excerpt from Syncthings homepage: Syncthing replaces proprietary sync and cloud services with something open, trustworthy and decentralized.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compressed RAM based block devices</title>
      <link>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20150111-zram/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20150111-zram/</guid>
      <description>From zram documentation: The zram module creates RAM based block devices named /dev/zram(= 0, 1, &amp;hellip;). Pages written to these disks are compressed and stored in memory itself. These disks allow very fast I/O and compression provides good amounts of memory savings. Some of the usecases include /tmp storage, use as swap disks, various caches under /var and maybe many more :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Record a PulseAudio sound stream</title>
      <link>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20150110-pa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20150110-pa/</guid>
      <description>Ever wondered on how to record the audio from one application? Either the browser or a streaming application that don&amp;rsquo;t have the option to save audio to a file.
The PulseAudio sound server in your desktop makes this quite easy.
I&amp;rsquo;ve created a small script that captures the current playing sound stream and redirects it to FLAC audio file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vagrant with OpenStack</title>
      <link>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20141218-vagrant-openstack/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20141218-vagrant-openstack/</guid>
      <description>If you want to use Vagrant with OpenStack, you need to prepare Vagrant with installing the vagrant-openstack-plugin. I had some problems installing it directly through vagrant plugin install. I had to clone it from Github and install it manually.
One time configuration Install OpenStack plugin in Vagrant cd /tmp git clone https://github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>fio - flexible I/O tester</title>
      <link>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20141215-fio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20141215-fio/</guid>
      <description>From man page: fio is a tool that will spawn a number of threads or processes doing a particular type of I/O action as specified by the user. The typical use of fio is to write a job file matching the I/O load one wants to simulate.
This example only show how to use fio to make reproduceable test on a file system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Power saving on laptop</title>
      <link>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20141214-powersave/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20141214-powersave/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Notes for power saving on my i5 laptop.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>View Google Earth in the browser</title>
      <link>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20140619-webgl/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20140619-webgl/</guid>
      <description>Google now supports Google Earth in Google Maps. As far as I know it works in Chrome and Chromium. If Google Earth isn&amp;rsquo;t available where the satellite view options is, your graphic card is in the browsers blacklist.
To force enabling WebGL in the browser start it with the following options</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vagrant, development environments made easy</title>
      <link>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20140525-vagrant/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20140525-vagrant/</guid>
      <description>Prototyping and testing configurations and system installations is time consuming on traditional hardware. That is why I started using Vagrant for nearly all development, prototyping and testing. It&amp;rsquo;s free and really easy to use. If you install VirtualBox sudo apt-get install virtualbox first, you&amp;rsquo;ll be up and running in no time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Only Firefox is safe post Heartblead</title>
      <link>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20140512-revocation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20140512-revocation/</guid>
      <description>oSteve Gibson have a nice round-up where he explains how certificate revocation does work and why Chrome and Chromiums certificate revocation scheme doesn&amp;rsquo;t work. I recommend to read both Steve Gibson&amp;lsquo;s article on An Evaluation of the Effectiveness of Chrome&amp;rsquo;s CRLSets and Adam Langley&amp;rsquo;s in my opinion a bit missplaced answer Revocation still doesn&amp;rsquo;t work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flashing a custom rom on Nexus 4</title>
      <link>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20140511-rootnexus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20140511-rootnexus/</guid>
      <description>Flashing a custom image on an Android mobile could be just fun. But if you don&amp;rsquo;t know why you want to do it, or do it just because it&amp;rsquo;s a challenge. Then don&amp;rsquo;t!
The bad and the good I&amp;rsquo;m only pointing out some of the cons and the pros here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OCSP Stapling on Apache</title>
      <link>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20140504-ocsp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20140504-ocsp/</guid>
      <description>Excerpt from Remy van Elsts tutorial: OCSP stapling is an enhancement to the standard OCSP protocol that delivers OCSP responses from the server with the certificate, eliminating the need for relying parties (web users) to check OCSP responses with the issuing CA. This has the effect of reducing bandwidth, improving perceived site performance, and increasing security for everyone involved in establishing the secure session.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Auto generate Pelican blog from Dropbox</title>
      <link>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20140503-dropbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20140503-dropbox/</guid>
      <description>This is my notes for how to update my Pelican blog automaticlly when I write new posts. See Creating a blog based on Pelican for getting started with Pelican blog engine.
A way to be able to blog from anywhere is to use Dropbox as repository for the your blog. Then let Pelican auto regenerate the blog on changes in the Dropbox folder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to get A&#43; on SSL Labs</title>
      <link>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20140503-ssl/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20140503-ssl/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This will show how to get A+ on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ssllabs.com/ssltest&#34;&gt;SSL Server Test&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ssllabs.com&#34;&gt;Qualys SSL Labs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>reStructuredText cheat sheet</title>
      <link>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20140503-rst/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20140503-rst/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;document&#34;&gt;


&lt;p&gt;My cheat sheet for &lt;a class=&#34;reference external&#34; href=&#34;http://docutils.sourceforge.net/docs/ref/rst/restructuredtext.html&#34;&gt;reStructuredText&lt;/a&gt; syntax with examples how it will look after parsing. &lt;a class=&#34;reference external&#34; href=&#34;http://docutils.sourceforge.net/docs/ref/rst/restructuredtext.html&#34;&gt;reStructuredText&lt;/a&gt; is an alternative for &lt;a class=&#34;reference external&#34; href=&#34;http://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown&#34;&gt;Markedown&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring OpenVPN server on RTN66U</title>
      <link>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20140501-easyrsa/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20140501-easyrsa/</guid>
      <description>The router firmware Tomato, see previous post RT-N66u with Tomato by Shibby firmware, can act as an OpenVPN server.
Using open Wi-Fi access points can be very useful and necessary, but it is inherently insecure. Using the router as an OpenVPN server can increase your privacy and security when you are on the go.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Better entropy with haveged</title>
      <link>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20140429-haveged/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20140429-haveged/</guid>
      <description>Entropy is important for generating good encryption keys. Do you have a busy server relying on crypto, generating keys, you need lot of good entropy. Or if you have a disk less system you don&amp;rsquo;t get as much entropy from the kernel that you may wish. One way to get a lot of good entropy is to use haveged.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RT-N66u with Tomato by Shibby firmware</title>
      <link>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20140417-tomato/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20140417-tomato/</guid>
      <description>This is a part of my personal notes. Use this information at your own risk. If you are uncertain or don&amp;rsquo;t know what you are doing. Do not proceed.
Asus RT-N66U is a Linux based wireless router. The stock firmware can be a bit limiting for the more advanced user. If you want better QoS, OpenVPN or just more control over the network I recommend installing Tomato by Shibby firmware.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Find duplicate files</title>
      <link>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20140413-duplicates/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2014 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20140413-duplicates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Find all duplicate files in current and sub-directories with bash.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remove unused kernels</title>
      <link>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20140413-kernel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2014 16:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20140413-kernel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Removes all but current kernel and headers. This is a note for personal use. Use at your own risk :)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bash getopts example</title>
      <link>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20140413-getopts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20140413-getopts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a small example how to use getopts in bash. I wrote it down for my own sake, as my own cheatsheet :)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud virtual machine</title>
      <link>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20140413-digitalocea/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20140413-digitalocea/</guid>
      <description>Easiest way I know to create cloud virtual machine is to create a Droplet on Digital Ocean.
 DigialOcean  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modeline in vim</title>
      <link>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20140413-modeline/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20140413-modeline/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Options set in &lt;code&gt;.vimrc&lt;/code&gt; applies to all vim files. You can use modelines to set specific vim options for one file. Modeline option must be set in &lt;code&gt;.vimrc&lt;/code&gt; to take advantage of this option.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SSL Server Test</title>
      <link>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20140413-ssllabs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20140413-ssllabs/</guid>
      <description>Run Qualys SSL Labs test to test the strength and combability of SSL certificate.
 SSL Server Test  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a blog based on Pelican</title>
      <link>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20140412-pelican/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20140412-pelican/</guid>
      <description>Pelican is a static website generator written in Python. It&amp;rsquo;s perfect for maintaining a tiny blog without having to mess around with databases. Static pages can be served from any Web server. Even your wireless router if you run custom firmware as Tomato by Shibby or dd-wrt.
Running Ubuntu Trusty I chose to use Pelican package in repository.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scaling in the Linux Networking Stack</title>
      <link>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20140412-link/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.heimsbakk.net/posts/20140412-link/</guid>
      <description>Documentation for increaseing parallelism and performance for multi-processor systems.
 scaling.html  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>